# MANDIP GIRI

# BASIC INFORMATION

Lalitpur Kathmandu mandipgiri@hotmail.com, +977 984 945 0329

Website: mandipgiri.com.np

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mandip-giri-02166080

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Competent ,hard working professional who can work under pressure and loves to face new challenges who has been in the industry for more than 6 years. Highly motivated and enthused individual with proper communication skills to be a team player.

A programming / technology enthusiast who is always ready to learn and grow.

## **EDUCATION**

Schooling
Ideal Model School

2013

Higher Secondary Level(+2) in Science

Prasadi Academy

Bachelor's in Computer Engineering 2017

Kantipur Engineering College

# SKILLS

- Javascript
- Typescript
- React
- React Native
- Redux with middlewares like Redux Saga/Redux Thunk
- Node JS
- Express JS
- AWS Services
- Android App Development (Java / Kotlin)

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Application Engineer July 2019 - Present

**AMNIL Technologies** 

As an Application Engineer at AMNIL Technologies was to develop mobile applications with React Native along with providing support to previous projects for feature enhancements and issue fixes. Also from time

This resume is made with CVwizard.com.

to time I provided support to frontend team on React JS projects and also mentor interns for React.As for my recent role for last project I have been doing Team Lead & Application Engineer where I was managing my team member's along with communicating with the client and closing communication gap with the team and client. Understand the requirement of the client and see that the team understands it and get it done.

Mobile App Developer Jan 2018 - July 2019

Hazesoft Pvt. Ltd

I was employed at Hazesoft as an mobile app developer (Android Native App developer/ React Native Developer). I had been developing React Native App in Hazesoft since Dec,2018 alongside Android Native Apps.My core responsibility is to look over all the current projects app-side, upgrade them with new technologies and features as required and fix bugs if any arises. I have previously worked at Hazesoft as a Junior Android Developer for approximately 4 months ,where I had delivered two apps in Java , in co ordinance with my Senior developers.

Android Internship Oct 2017 - Dec 2017

Hazesoft Pvt. Ltd

Learned about android development processes and its architecture, software development life cycles in a real world project

Software Engineer Jan 2022 - Jul 2023

Cloudfactory

As a Software Engineer at Cloudfactory, I had been working as a fullstack developer for a internal tool of the company. I had been working to develop features along with understanding domains. I had been grooming myself to new tech stack that included React with NodeJS in BFF pattern followed by Golang and AWS. In this time I also had mentored interns.

#### Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2023 - Current

Cloudfactory

I am continuing the same work I did as a Software Engineer but now I get more involved in technical and architecture decisions. Since I have nieche experience in React, I help other team members and lead different improvements and try to drive and set standards for React and help them introduce to new tech in React itself.

#### PROJECTS WORKED ON

Android Native Projects:

Hayn Customer App

Hayn Provider App

Lugmety Customer App

Lugmety Driver App

Lugmety Restaurant App

Albagal

Dokaan

Yummy

Lugmety Driver App v2

Lugmety Customer App

React-Native Projects:

HR PIE

DishHome Care

cdmSmith

ePharmacy Nepal

Nagarik News

Hamro Nirman

Mamut ERP (Magro)

Vesta Home

Vesta Partner

Personal Projects

e commerce using React JS and firebase - https://omg-clothing.herokuapp.com/Covid Tracking with MERN stack - https://covid19-mern.herokuapp.com/

College Projects

Project Aider - We developed web application for repository and project and task collaboration using Java for final year project.

Restaurant Management System - We built a desktop app using Java platform which managed the employee records, menus and calculated bills. The app also showed graph of most sold food items for minor project.

Departmental Billing System -We designed a system for calculating the bills for a supermarket using C++. Hotel Management System - We designed a system that reserved the room and calculated the total bill of the customer using C.

#### **INTERESTS**

Coding Learning new technologies/languages in programming Cooking Music

#### REFERENCES

- Er.Dipesh Shrestha Project Assistant, Kantipur Engineering College, Dhapakhel, Lalitpur
- Mr. Bijay Luitel CTO, Hazesoft Pvt. Ltd
- Mr. Niroj Maharjan Sr. Android Developer
- Mr. Bedh Raj Dhakal Software Engineer
- Mr. Chewang Yolmoo Senior Software Engineer
- Mr. Yuba Raj Oli Application Engineer
- Mr. Mahan Adhikari Senior Software Engineer
- Mr. Sunil Poudel Senior Software Engineer
- Mr. Samit Ghimire Lead Engineer